<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Science for Business Applications 2021 on Social Data Science 2021</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/</link><description>Recent content in Data Science for Business Applications 2021 on Social Data Science 2021</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basics Statistical Programming</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/02_basics/01_stat_prog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/02_basics/01_stat_prog/</guid><description>Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
This session is a basic introduction to statistical programming as well as a short brush-up on data more generally. For some, this will be &amp;ldquo;old news&amp;rdquo;, but many will certainly benefit from reviewing this material. We start with a generall theory lecture on data structures and properties, and then dive into R and Python specific applications of statistical programming.</description></item><item><title>Day 1</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/04_workshops/w1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/04_workshops/w1/</guid><description>Practical info Place: DHØ 1.23 Time: 8:15 (we start 15 min later) - 13:20
Schedule for the day Time Activity Data Session 1 8:15-9:45 EDA and DataViz Open Policing Session 2 10:00-11:30 EDA and UML Digital Nomads Session 3 12:00-13:20 UML continued. Digital Nomads Datasets &amp;amp; Context Open policing project The Stanford Open Policing Dataset records trafic stops by US police including data on the vehicle, driver, violation, outcome and many more variables.</description></item><item><title>Exercise 1 - EDA withDigital Nomads</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/00_assignments/exercise1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/00_assignments/exercise1/</guid><description>This is not an assignment, just a voluntary exercise for you to test if you grasp the concepts in the corresponding topics. It does not have to be handed in anywhere
Data You are given 2 datasets from https://nomadlist.com - A community page for remote workers worldwide. Further, you are provided with a countries list, a dataset containing information on countries, regions and countrycodes.
Trips data: holds ~46k individual trips of travelers on the platform.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/01_infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/01_infrastructure/</guid><description>Main Infrastructure MS teams : Join our MS our teams channel to get updates from us, Q&amp;amp;A, and talk to your peers. Canvas : We will not use it from now on for content, but for the sake of completeness. However, you will still find your calendar there and we may use it from time to time to send out mass-mails to you all. Datacamp : Get access to all the Datacamp premium content for free to facilitate your data science journey.</description></item><item><title>Unsupervised Machine Learning (UML)</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/03_ml/01_uml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/03_ml/01_uml/</guid><description> Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
This session introduces unsupervised machine learning (UML)
Recommended Datacamp exercises: Python R Theory: Unsupervised ML R Application - UML Python Application - UML Video Slides Use arrows keys on keyboard to navigate. Alternatively fullscreen slides available here Follow along HTML Notebook Colab Notebook Video 1: EDA &amp; Dimensionality Reduction Video 2: Clustering Follow along Colab Notebook Video 1: EDA &amp; Dimensionality Reduction Video 2: EDA &amp; Clustering</description></item><item><title>Basics Data Manipulation</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/02_basics/02_data_manipulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/02_basics/02_data_manipulation/</guid><description>Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
This session introduces some fundamental concepts of data manipulation and Exploratory Data Analysis. We will again start with a theoretical lecture on fundamental concepts and techniques in data manipulation, and afterwards again explore them in R and Python specific applications. These applications are complemented by recap exercises to test yourself.
Theory: Fundamentals of Data Manipulation R Application - Data Manipulation Python Application - Data Manipulation Video Slides Use arrows keys on keyboard to navigate.</description></item><item><title>Day 2</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/04_workshops/w2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/04_workshops/w2/</guid><description>Practical info Place: K 143 Time: 11:40 - 17:00
Schedule for the day Time Activity Data Session 1 11:40-13:00 SML - Regression AirBnb Session 2 13:20-14:50 SML - Regression and intro classification AirBnb Session 3 15:00-16:30 SML - Classification HR Session 4 16:40-17:00 Wrapup, Assignment handout -</description></item><item><title>Exerciset 2 - UML with Pokemon</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/00_assignments/exercise2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/00_assignments/exercise2/</guid><description>This is not an assignment, just a voluntary exercise for you to test if you grasp the concepts in the corresponding topics. It does not have to be handed in anywhere
Description This time you will work with Pokemon data. No data munging needed. Just old-school (U)ML.
Data The data is available through the URL: https://sds-aau.github.io/SDS-master/00_data/pokemon.csv. It contains data on 800 Pokemon from the 1st to the 6th generation.</description></item><item><title>Intro Talk - Data Science in business</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/01_warmup/01_business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/01_warmup/01_business/</guid><description> Use the tabs to access content
This Video series contains a 3-part talk by Daniel and Roman on data science applications in business
Follow along:
Slides DS in business 1 - Current state 2 - Intro ML 3 - DS Teams Data Science in business 1 - Current state Data Science in business 2 - Introduction to Machine Learning Data Science in business 3 -Team and Roles</description></item><item><title>Supervised Machine Learning (SML)</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/03_ml/02_sml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/03_ml/02_sml/</guid><description>Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
This session introduces unsupervised machine learning (UML)
Recommended Datacamp exercises: Python - Intro to supervised learning Python - Decision Tree modeling R - Supervised classification R - Supervised Regression Theory: Supervised ML R Application - SML Python Application - SML Video 1: Introduction &amp; Statistics Refresher Video 2: Generalization, Model Classes &amp; Tuning Slides Use arrows keys on keyboard to navigate.</description></item><item><title>Basics Data Visualization</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/02_basics/03_data_visualization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/02_basics/03_data_visualization/</guid><description>Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
This session introduces some fundamental concepts of data visualization. After a theoretical lecture on types and dimensions of data visualization, we will explore the visualization of different data types, structure, and properties in R and Python specific applications.
Theory: Elements of Data Visualization R Application - Data Visualization Python Application - Data Visualization Video Slides Use arrows keys on keyboardto navigate.</description></item><item><title>Modules</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/02_modules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/02_modules/</guid><description>The course is structured in 3 modules.
M1: Applied Data Science and Machine Learning This module will prove a condensed introduction to the “Data Science Pipeline”, introducing students to methods, techniques, and workflows in applied data analytics and machine learning, including data acquisition, preparation, analysis, visualization, and communication.
M2: Network Analysis and Natural Language Processing Focuses on analyzing a variety of unstructured data sources. Particularly, students will learn how to explore, analyze, and visualize natural language (text) as well as relational (network) data.</description></item><item><title>Literature &amp; Resources</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/04_litetrature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/04_litetrature/</guid><description>While this course does not come with a list of mandatory readings, we will often refer to some central resources in R and python, which for the most part can always be accessed in a free and updated online version. We generally recommend you to use these amazing resources for problem-solving and further self-study on the topic.
Main Literature These pieces of work can be seen as main references for data science using R and Python.</description></item><item><title>Semester Schedule</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/03_schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/03_schedule/</guid><description>M1: Week 36-38 Topics W 36: Data Manipulation, Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA), Data Visualization W 37: Unsupervised Machine Learning (UML), Supervised Machine Learning (SML) W 38: Workshop &amp;amp; project work M2: Week 39-41 Topics W 39: Introduction to Network Analysis W 40: Introduction to Natural-Language-Processing (NLP) W 41: Workshop &amp;amp; project work M3: Week 43-46 Topics W 43: Introduction to Artificial Neural Networks (ANN) &amp;amp; Deep Learning (DL) W 44: Neural networks for spatial data: Recurrent Neural Networks (RNN) W 45: Neural Networks for sequential data: Recurrent Neural networks (RNN &amp;amp; LSTM) W 46: Workshop &amp;amp; project work Key Dates In-person workshops on CBS campus (always Thursday + Friday)</description></item><item><title>Final Project Requirements</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/05_requirements_project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/05_requirements_project/</guid><description>To be updated soon</description></item><item><title>The Data Science Ecosystem</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/01_warmup/02_ecosystem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/01_warmup/02_ecosystem/</guid><description> Use the tabs to access content
This Video series contains an introduction to the data science ecosystem, includng a general as well as a R and Python specific overview.
R Ecosystem Python Ecosystem DS Ecosystem general Video Slides Video Slides Video Slides</description></item></channel></rss>