<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Info, Schedule &amp; Co on Social Data Science 2021</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/</link><description>Recent content in Info, Schedule &amp; Co on Social Data Science 2021</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Infrastructure</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/01_infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/01_infrastructure/</guid><description>Main Infrastructure MS teams : Join our MS our teams channel to get updates from us, Q&amp;amp;A, and talk to your peers. Canvas : We will not use it from now on for content, but for the sake of completeness. However, you will still find your calendar there and we may use it from time to time to send out mass-mails to you all. Datacamp : Get access to all the Datacamp premium content for free to facilitate your data science journey.</description></item><item><title>Modules</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/02_modules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/02_modules/</guid><description>The course is structured in 3 modules.
M1: Applied Data Science and Machine Learning This module will prove a condensed introduction to the “Data Science Pipeline”, introducing students to methods, techniques, and workflows in applied data analytics and machine learning, including data acquisition, preparation, analysis, visualization, and communication.
M2: Network Analysis and Natural Language Processing Focuses on analyzing a variety of unstructured data sources. Particularly, students will learn how to explore, analyze, and visualize natural language (text) as well as relational (network) data.</description></item><item><title>Literature &amp; Resources</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/04_litetrature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/04_litetrature/</guid><description>While this course does not come with a list of mandatory readings, we will often refer to some central resources in R and python, which for the most part can always be accessed in a free and updated online version. We generally recommend you to use these amazing resources for problem-solving and further self-study on the topic.
Main Literature These pieces of work can be seen as main references for data science using R and Python.</description></item><item><title>Semester Schedule</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/03_schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/03_schedule/</guid><description>M1: Week 36-38 Topics W 36: Data Manipulation, Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA), Data Visualization W 37: Unsupervised Machine Learning (UML), Supervised Machine Learning (SML) W 38: Workshop &amp;amp; project work M2: Week 39-41 Topics W 39: Introduction to Network Analysis W 40: Introduction to Natural-Language-Processing (NLP) W 41: Workshop &amp;amp; project work M3: Week 43-46 Topics W 43: Introduction to Artificial Neural Networks (ANN) &amp;amp; Deep Learning (DL) W 44: Neural networks for spatial data: Recurrent Neural Networks (RNN) W 45: Neural Networks for sequential data: Recurrent Neural networks (RNN &amp;amp; LSTM) W 46: Workshop &amp;amp; project work Key Dates In-person workshops on CBS campus (always Thursday + Friday)</description></item><item><title>Final Project Requirements</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/05_requirements_project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/info/05_requirements_project/</guid><description>To be updated soon</description></item></channel></rss>