<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Assignments on Social Data Science 2021</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m2/00_assignments/</link><description>Recent content in Assignments on Social Data Science 2021</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m2/00_assignments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exercise 1 - Network Analysis</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m2/00_assignments/exercise1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m2/00_assignments/exercise1/</guid><description>Introduction In th first Part 2, you will replicate a well known network analysis, with different data and some twists. Data: The data is to be found at: https://github.com/SDS-AAU/SDS-master/tree/master/00_data/network_krackhard (Hint: You neet to download the raw data) Data: What do I get? Background Let the fun begin. You will analyze network datacollected from the managers of a high-tec company. This dataset, originating from the paper below, is widely used in research on organizational networks.</description></item><item><title>Exercise t 2 - NLP</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m2/00_assignments/exercise2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m2/00_assignments/exercise2/</guid><description>Introduction: Building a Hate Speech Classifier This assignment is less structured than previous individual assignments.
You are given a collection of approximately 25k tweets that have been manually (human) annotated. class denotes: 0 - hate speech, 1 - offensive language, 2 - neither
https://github.com/SDS-AAU/SDS-master/raw/master/M2/data/twitter_hate.zip
1. Preprocessing and vectorizaion. Justify your choices and explain possible alternatives (e.g. removing stopwords, identifying bi/tri-grams, removing verbs or use of stemming, lemmatization etc.)
Create a bag-of-words representation, apply TF-IDF and dimensionality reduction (LSA-topic modelling alternatively simply PCA or SVD) to transform your corpus into a feature matrix.</description></item><item><title>M2 (Mandatory) Assignment</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m2/00_assignments/group_assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m2/00_assignments/group_assignment/</guid><description>DSBA 2021 - M2: (Mandatory) Assignment Introduction xxxxx
Now it is time to bring most these steps together and apply them to a setting that you find interesting. This should apply the following tasks.
Identify an interesting problem that can be tackled using netork analysis and NLP techniques. Optimally, this is done within one dataset. However, the assignment can also be done using 2 different datasets, if nothing suitable combinging both elements of netork analysis and NLP is found.</description></item></channel></rss>