<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Basics of Statistical Programming and Data Manipulation (36) on Social Data Science 2021</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/02_basics/</link><description>Recent content in Basics of Statistical Programming and Data Manipulation (36) on Social Data Science 2021</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/02_basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basics Statistical Programming</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/02_basics/01_stat_prog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/02_basics/01_stat_prog/</guid><description>Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
This session is a basic introduction to statistical programming as well as a short brush-up on data more generally. For some, this will be &amp;ldquo;old news&amp;rdquo;, but many will certainly benefit from reviewing this material. We start with a generall theory lecture on data structures and properties, and then dive into R and Python specific applications of statistical programming.</description></item><item><title>Basics Data Manipulation</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/02_basics/02_data_manipulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/02_basics/02_data_manipulation/</guid><description>Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
This session introduces some fundamental concepts of data manipulation and Exploratory Data Analysis. We will again start with a theoretical lecture on fundamental concepts and techniques in data manipulation, and afterwards again explore them in R and Python specific applications. These applications are complemented by recap exercises to test yourself.
Theory: Fundamentals of Data Manipulation R Application - Data Manipulation Python Application - Data Manipulation Video Slides Use arrows keys on keyboard to navigate.</description></item><item><title>Basics Data Visualization</title><link>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/02_basics/03_data_visualization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sds-aau.github.io/DSBA-2021/m1/02_basics/03_data_visualization/</guid><description>Use the tabs to access content. Theory part is general, R &amp;amp; Python application part language specific.
This session introduces some fundamental concepts of data visualization. After a theoretical lecture on types and dimensions of data visualization, we will explore the visualization of different data types, structure, and properties in R and Python specific applications.
Theory: Elements of Data Visualization R Application - Data Visualization Python Application - Data Visualization Video Slides Use arrows keys on keyboardto navigate.</description></item></channel></rss>